As you can see, the stance for a man is a different position.
They don't pull the feet in like the women, they leave the basic open, so that first position is an open position, again the toes are diagonal, not pointing straight ahead but with about a foot of distance between each other.
You're able to hit first position, or what we like to call basic in modeling.
What I'd like to do from this position is show the men how they can go ahead and sit down in a professional way.
The best thing for them to do is move into their chair where their leg also touches the seat of the chair and as they go down, they do not have to worry about their knees touching.
So as they sit down, again keeping perfect posture, they use their hands to guide them to the edge of their seat, not worrying about their knees being together, and they move into the middle of the chair, keeping or adjusting if you'd like to say, the basic stance for a man.
It's the same sitting as it is standing.
One thing that's really important for men to remember while they're sitting, is that their legs stay positioned inside the legs of the chair.
Whatever chair they choose to sit in, that's the amount of space that they should use.
It's etiquette, it's professional and that's the amount of space that they should use for their chair.
Keep their legs inside the legs of their chair.
The knees are open and the hands just rest on the thigh.
As you can see, they don't need to bring them to the side, that's more feminine.
So I'd like for the men just to be relaxed with their perfect posture, and rest their hands on the top of the thighs of their legs.
So now that you've seen how a man should sit into a chair just a little bit different than how ladies do, they don't keep their knees together, they can keep them apart, about a foot apart.
They let their hands just rest on their thighs and by still attaining perfect posture, keeping the shoulders down, slightly back but relaxed and the stomach muscles in, again, when you're sitting keep your stomach muscles in so that your chest expands and you feel relaxed and comfortable.
This is exactly what men should do before they begin to get up.
But as they get up, keep in mind it's not one movement.
You want to gently slide to the edge of your hair and then with a straight back, use just the knees to pop you back up out of the chair in order to move on or walk away.